Dharmendra Puri

P: 0452 629 425 | E: dharmendra.puri@icloud.com | W: https://dharmendrapuri.github.io/dharmendrapuri/

SUMMARY

Having serviced the Prince of Qatar, the New Zealand cricket team, and 60,000+ other customers at a 5-start Sydney hotel, I enjoy building relationships with people from diverse backgrounds and pride myself in impeccable end-to-end customer service. Complementing this is a Master's in Information Technology and Hotel Management, and professional IT certifications, which provide me with strong programming language, project management, and software skills: SQL, R, Tableau, Advanced Microsoft Excel, HTML, CSS, PHP, & Power BI. Having 5.5 years of experience in freelance data analyst, workshop coordination, hospitality, and administration, I have also become a highly organized and collaborative problem solver. I value helping businesses improve their efficiency and service and am extremely interested in junior IT support/data analyst/ web developer/ database administrator roles.

KEY SKILLS

- Management/Problem Solving Managed 100+ workshops and events for high profile companies to ensure smooth event operations, increase customer satisfaction rates by 10%, and increase revenue by 15%.
- Computer Networking Familiar with TCP/IP Protocol, different Routing Protocols, and general Desktop and Customer Support Skills
- **Web Development** Created a website for project in Uni using Laravel PHP framework, gained intermediate knowledge of HTML, CSS, PHP, & JavaScript.
- Database Design, Analysis & Visualisation—Developed database schema leveraging data models, entity relationship diagrams (ERD) based on business requirements and deployed in SQL Server and MySQL for 15+ small companies over 3 months. Acquired strong understanding of testing methodologies. Familiar with SQL Server and MSBI ETL tools like SSIS, SSAS, & SSRS. Certified Tableau Desktop Specialist.
- Machine Learning, Data Warehouse & Mining Applied association rule mining, classification, and clustering methods on large supermarket data sets. Bootcamp certified in advanced SQL and R data wrangling and manipulation. Familiar with Python libraries Pandas & NumPy
- **Programming Languages** Exposed to C#, JavaScript, Intermediate knowledge in R, & Intermediate Knowledge in Python.
- Cloud Computing Familiar with AWS EC2, RDS, Google Compute Engine, Azure Database, Cosmos DB, and Databricks.

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst Intern, Customer Crunch

Oct 2020 – Present

- Building visualizations, dashboards, and reports, and helping data scientist for a new product development.
- Cleaning the dataset using SQL, and EXCEL and prepare the extract for the report.

Freelance Data Analyst, Upwork

Mar 2020 – Present

• Built interactive/dynamic dashboards, reports, and descriptive/predictive/prescriptive analysis via advanced Microsoft Excel Pivot Tables and Tableau Dashboards for 15+ companies over 6 months.

Data Analyst (Virtual Intern), KPMG

September 2020 – October 2020

• Performed data quality analysis, created analytical dashboards, applied customer segmentation techniques, and developed data driven presentations.

Guest Service Agent, Fraser Suites Sydney

Jan 2018 – Mar 2020

- Served 200+ customers per day (60,000+ total) to deliver exceptional end-to-end customer service.
- Created, modified, and reported on data cross-department within property management software to ensure accurate data and facilitate smooth customer experiences.

• Owned monthly sales reporting to ensure effective communication with management.

Conference Coordinator, Hilton Sydney

Jun 2016 - Jan 2018

- Conducted 100+ successful workshops and events and 5,000+ individual customers with high profile organisations to increase customer satisfaction rates by 10% and increase revenue by 15%.
- Liaised with organisers, managers, sales, and food/beverage teams to ensure smooth events.

Aid Worker, **USAID**

Dec 2015 - May 2016

• Participated in the Earthquake Relief Program in Nepal to reconstruct rural village infrastructure.

Admin Support, London College Of Commerce

Jul 2013 – Dec 2015

- Conducted training program for 500+ students to ensure effective administrative operations.
- Communicated with lecturers, students, and other staff to provide efficient admin support.

EDUCATION

Master of Applied Information Technology, Victoria University	2018 - 2020
Master of International Hotel Management, BMIHMS at Torrens University	2016 - 2018
Tableau Desktop Specialist	2020
Analysing Data with Power BI, Microsoft certification	2020
Microsoft Azure Data Fundamental	2020

Thank you for considering my application. I would love to discuss this opportunity with you and am excited to hear back.